<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tingling Neurons</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tingling Neurons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>And welcome to my blog ‘Tingling Neurons’!
This is a space where I am sharing my thoughts, stories and views on the world. Or get them straight in the first place, since it is often a little bit chaotic in my head 😉
Maybe you are interested in similar topics like me: product management, personal development, productivity, work, philosophy, (neuro-) physiology, travelling and great stories.
And why Tingling Neurons? I like medicine (particularly Physiology) and I am totally amazed by how much can change, if we change our mindset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Ace your OKRs</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-ace-your-okrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-ace-your-okrs/</guid>
      <description>OKRs are usually viewed as a tool to track progress towards a specific goal. They are set up depending on what the company is planning to do or based on a problem the company has at that point in time.
However, this does not leverage the whole power of OKRs.
What are OKRs? OKRs are objective key results. They are usually defined within a quarter, but they can also contribute to a goal that you want to achieve within a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals</title>
      <link>/posts/goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/goals/</guid>
      <description>This year, I reflected a lot on who I am and what I want to do with my life.
Even though I do not have it all figured out yet (who has?), I learned a few important lessons about goals along the way. That is about the different kind of goals there are, how to size them, when they are useful and when they are not, how to keep track of them and how I want to implement them into my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Motivation</title>
      <link>/posts/finding-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/finding-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had a real low in motivation, and it was pretty hard for me to put in the effort at work, which is something I do not experience often, so it was quite a bummer. Why? This is not something I would really want to discuss here, but to break it down: I had a few realizations about the company I work for and a few realizations about myself, which were tough for me to accept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain Fog</title>
      <link>/posts/brain-fog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/brain-fog/</guid>
      <description>Brain fog is, when you feel like there is kind of fog around your thinking. You are not focused, you feel like you are daydreaming all the time and whenever you try to concentrate, it takes a ton of energy.
I experienced this for a while, and it was annoying me so much, I did a quick, but intense research on the topic. Here is what helped me:
Eat a lot of fiber Not the first thought one might have, but definitely what helped me most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Negotiation</title>
      <link>/posts/negotiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/negotiation/</guid>
      <description>Negotiation is a skill I only recently learned about. As some of you might know, I am a Product and Content manager at Greator. And for our Business Coach program, I recently shot with Jack Nasher, THE Negotiation expert in Germany. Since I did not think about negotiation a lot before, I want to share with you, what I have learned, and what really surprised me about the topic.
The Just World Phenomenon / Theory Melvin Lerner (I love his name), a social psychologist, created the Just Word Phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neurophysiology of Learning</title>
      <link>/posts/neurophysiology-of-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/neurophysiology-of-learning/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered how learning works exactly? After reading this article, you will know exactly what is happening in your brain, whenever you learn something new.
Storing memories Many experts believe that we store memories via a three-step process: first, we perceive information via our senses, then we store and process it in short-term memory, and finally, some memories, we store in long-term memory. Since we do not need to retain everything in our brain, the process acts as a filter that protects us from the flood of information we are confronted with every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Midnight Library – Regretting Life Decisions</title>
      <link>/posts/the-midnight-library-regretting-life-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-midnight-library-regretting-life-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Is your life full of regrets? A friend recommended the book “The midnight library” by Matt Haig to me. She read it in her vacation and said, that it is one of those books, that is packaging personal development into a beautiful story. And I have to say I agree. It is a wonderful and easy read, with a lot of take-aways. If you are struggling with regret, it might be the perfect book for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity hacks</title>
      <link>/posts/productivity-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/productivity-hacks/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to share some hacks on how I keep myself productive and efficient. These are some things, that really made my work life easier and made it possible to follow my personal projects.
Plan ahead Every week I reflect on what went well and what I would have liked to be different. Also I usually would try to find the root cause, if I am not happy with something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the right skills</title>
      <link>/posts/building-the-right-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/building-the-right-skills/</guid>
      <description>Here are some thoughts about how to develop the right skills for a life you want to live. Last week I had an interesting discussion with a friend about different kind of skills. In case you are wandering, what exactly we mean by skills, we defined it as applied knowledge. Knowledge can be gathered by passive or active learning or simply by experiences we make.
Skill development is also a topic I currently want to focus on more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19 Tips for better Sleep</title>
      <link>/posts/19-tips-for-better-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/19-tips-for-better-sleep/</guid>
      <description>I am known for talking a lot about sleep. Why? It is just a wonderful and fascinating topic, since sleep can have a drastic impact on your life.
Why do we sleep? There are a lot of different theories on why we sleep and what it does to our body and especially to our brain. From an evolutionary perspective it doesn’t make sense at all. Why would nature knock us out for hours, in which we are then not able to protect us, look for food and reproduce?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to &#39;Slice the Elephant&#39;</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-slice-the-elephant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-slice-the-elephant/</guid>
      <description>This post is based on a simple idea: If you have a lot on your plate or a big project coming up – slice the elephant. That means break down that ‘super huge and overwhelming thing’ into pieces. And then make a plan for handling these pieces.
But as simple as this idea is, the hardest part is often to get that this is what you need to do, especially when you are stressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I wrote my Bachelor Thesis: Minimum Input, Maximum Output</title>
      <link>/posts/how-i-wrote-my-bachelor-thesis-minimum-input-maximum-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-i-wrote-my-bachelor-thesis-minimum-input-maximum-output/</guid>
      <description>Hey folks,
let’s talk about academic papers. I haven’t met a single person that loved them. I met a few that found meaning im them and I met a few that liked consuming the work of others, but I never really met anyone who is “passionate” about writing them. Not even writers. So in this blogpost I share a 9 tips, that will make it a whole lot easier to write academic papers and stop procrastinating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>about</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/</guid>
      <description>blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in touch</title>
      <link>/Get-in-touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Get-in-touch/</guid>
      <description>Get in touch</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
